# BRANDON BAUTISTA

## CONTACT

Phone: 517.420.3459 Email: bbautista@gmail.com

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

HubSpot Academy: Inbound Marketing, Content Marketing, Email Marketing, Social Media Marketing

Institute for Social and Emotional Intelligence: Social + Emotional Intelligence Certification

# **INVOLVEMENT**

Virtual Learning Leadership Alliance (VLLA) Co-chair of the National Marketing & Communications Group (2019-2022)

Michigan Education Policy Fellowship Program (EPFP) 2019-2020 Cohort

Founding member of *Michigan Virtual's* Culture Committee and its

Customer Experience (CX) Committee

# **HONORS**

**BUFFER**: Top 75 Social Media Marketers (2016)

37th Annual Educational
Advertising Awards:
Best Educational Podcast (for
"BRIGHT: Stories of Hope and
Innovation in Michigan Classrooms")

## **EDUCATION**

**Michigan State University**East Lansing, Michigan
Major: Telecommunications

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I'm a collaborative marketing leader with 25 years of experience in the online learning space. I believe great marketing isn't about outspending competitors; it's about out-connecting them, using storytelling to help people see themselves in what you're offering. My approach blends strategic focus with emotional intelligence: serving the human first, fostering a positive team culture, and delivering thoughtful, high-impact campaigns. Be kind. Work hard. Have fun.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Director of Marketing**

Michigan Virtual | 2022 — Present

- Develops and executes integrated marketing strategies across four revenue streams to increase brand visibility, successfully launch new learning products and services, and drive sustained engagement and growth
- Leads a high-performing in-house marketing team of specialists, overseeing strategy and execution across campaigns while supporting individual growth through collaborative professional development planning
- Oversees brand, voice, and messaging alignment across all marketing initiatives to strengthen trust, reduce revision cycles, and maintain quality, ensuring efficient content production and mission-aligned communications
- Serves as organizational HubSpot administrator and SME, leading CRM segmentation and workflow automation for 160,000+ contacts to increase qualified leads, reduce manual processes, and support sales team efficiency and conversion
- Built and scaled Michigan Virtual's social media presence from zero to over 31,000 combined followers across Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, YouTube, and X, expanding brand visibility, driving audience engagement, and supporting enrollment and awareness campaigns across multiple departments
- Founding member of the company's Customer Experience (CX) Team, collaborating across departments to identify pain points, improve touchpoints, and champion a seamless, customer-centered experience
- Provides project management leadership within the marketing team and across departments, serving as a Wrike super user to streamline workflows, prioritize tasks, and ensure on-time, high-quality deliverables, overseeing the successful completion of 1,300+ marketing tasks in the past year
- Led multi-phase digital ad strategy generating 17.4M+ impressions and 70K+ clicks with a 0.40% CTR over the past year, surpassing industry benchmarks and driving high-volume traffic to digital learning products, increasing awareness and conversions
- Supports the sales team's conference and event presence by coordinating booth materials, ensuring brand-aligned collateral, and overseeing the approval and selection of swag and giveaway items to enhance brand recall, increase prospect engagement, and contribute to lead generation efforts

# **BRANDON BAUTISTA**

# **WORK EXPERIENCE, CONTINUED**

## **Assistant Director of Marketing**

Michigan Virtual | 2020 — 2022

- Executed marketing strategies in alignment with organizational priorities, partnering closely with the Senior
  Director of Sales and Marketing to drive growth across digital and traditional channels and optimize lead
  generation for the sales team, contributing to increased pipeline volume and revenue growth
- Led a multidisciplinary in-house marketing team, including writers, content creators, graphic designers, a video producer, and web developers, reducing production turnaround times and increasing campaign effectiveness across key revenue-generating initiatives
- Facilitated emergency remote learning outreach during COVID-19 school closures by quickly launching a statewide website for free online course access, promoting the initiative to all Michigan K-12 personnel and families, and producing a webinar series to support teachers in rapidly transitioning to virtual instruction
- Produced an award-winning podcast spotlighting innovative Michigan educators, elevating teacher voices, and positively positioning the organization as a champion of educational innovation and excellence
- Contributed to the annual budgeting process, collaborating with the Senior Director of Sales and Marketing to allocate marketing resources effectively and support departmental and organizational goals

# **Marketing Manager**

Michigan Virtual | 2017 — 2020

- Assisted a major organizational rebranding effort, including the development of the new brand guide and voice, rollout across web, social media, and partner organizations, with a comprehensive communications plan
- Implemented sales pipelines in HubSpot, informed by best practices of inbound marketing and sales enablement
- Conducted market research and analyzed data to identify customer needs and preferences, developed personas, and used insights to inform marketing strategy
- Managed digital marketing campaigns across a variety of channels, including email, social media, and search engines, and tracked and reported on campaign performance
- · Developed and managed marketing budgets and allocated resources effectively to maximize ROI
- Built relationships with external partners and vendors to support marketing efforts and drive business objectives

# Social Media Manager

Michigan Virtual | 2016 — 2017

- Co-developed and executed a comprehensive social media strategy incorporating competitive research, platform selection, benchmarking, messaging, and audience identification
- Provided training and ongoing support for consistent implementation of organizational social media frameworks across programmatic initiatives
- Monitored all company brands on a daily basis to enhance organizational presence through targeted social platforms, as per the annual electronic marketing strategy
- Developed, implemented, monitored, and analyzed an annual editorial calendar and syndication schedule that reflected organizational objectives and key results

# Digital Media Manager

Michigan Virtual | 2006 — 2016

- Provided training and assistance to Michigan Virtual High School instructors on the use and implementation of multimedia resources in the courses
- Worked with the instructional designers and subject matter experts on the creation of original multimedia resources (video, audio, Flash), as well as quality assurance across all courses
- Evaluated and implemented leased third-party multimedia elements in the redesign and development of courses

Other roles at Michigan Virtual: Helpdesk Technician (2000-2001), Web Production Assistant (2001-2004), Enrollment Systems Administrator (2004-2006)